<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Troy Hamilton</title>
    <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Troy Hamilton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 10:36:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://troyhamilton.cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>This post is brought to you by the letters NSA</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/02/this-post-is-brought-to-you-by-the-letters-nsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 10:36:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/02/this-post-is-brought-to-you-by-the-letters-nsa/</guid>
      <description>In 1997 I recall my VB6 college professor Mr. Shroff asked us to name a programming language. At the time I was studying for my AA in Electronic Engineering but I was also working at CompUSA which is probably the best job I ever had. It was the catalyst for me into IT. Anyway, Mr. Shroff looks at me, asks me to name a language, and after a brief moment I remember chatting with Brandon at the upgrades counter at work and his new jump on Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pscp and psftp are your friends</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/pscp-and-psftp-are-your-friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 07:54:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/pscp-and-psftp-are-your-friends/</guid>
      <description>As magical as Hugo is, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the github deployment to work cleanly no matter how much I followed the official deployment guide on Windows 10 1809. When adding the submodule for the blog repo, this error kept pestering me:
&#39;public&#39; does not have a commit checked out All google-fu points to git v2.25.0.windows.1 and hugo extended v0.63.2 not being happy with each other. Luckily I have a CentOS vm that I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for my RHCSA labs and deploying my hugo blog to github ran clean with no errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When in doubt, check your routes</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/when-in-doubt-check-your-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 07:54:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/when-in-doubt-check-your-routes/</guid>
      <description>One of the cool things you can do when launching aws ec2 instances is add a configuration script that will run during launch. From the launch configuration wizard, this script is on the &amp;lsquo;Configure Instance Details&amp;rsquo; step under &amp;lsquo;Advanced Details&amp;rsquo;. A common script that I&amp;rsquo;ve been using lately with all of my labs is installing, starting, and enabling the apache web server aka httpd.
#!/bin/bash sudo yum update -y sudo yum install -y httpd php sudo systemctl start httpd sudo systemctl enable httpd This is just a batch script that will update yum, install apache and php, start the httpd daemon and enable it to start on next boot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the hugs for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/all-the-hugs-for-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 13:52:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/all-the-hugs-for-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am not a front end developer&amp;hellip;
14 years in IT, I regret not learning more html/css/js. That negligence has brought me to this point.
There&amp;rsquo;s a big difference between working with html files hosted in a load balanced IIS cluster versus building a site from scratch, tweaking it, making it look good, etc.
Before Hugo I tried:
 Rolling my own with html 5 and css 3 - Way harder than it sounds [fail] Gatsby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with AWS EC2 and puTTy</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/fun-with-aws-ec2-and-putty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 13:52:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/fun-with-aws-ec2-and-putty/</guid>
      <description>In preparation for SAA-C01 I wanted to start looking into moving my site from Github+Netlify to EC2+S3+Jenkins. So I go to ssh into my free-tier instance from PuTTy on win10 and I get:
No supported authentication methods available (server sent: publickey,gssapi-keyex,gssapi-with-mic Interesting, but ok, let&amp;rsquo;s see what&amp;rsquo;s wrong. So I login to aws console and verify my ec2 instance is running. The green dot means running right :). But we&amp;rsquo;re architects/engineers/sysops/devops so we do things in cli right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A world of hellos</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/a-world-of-hellos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 01:54:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/posts/2020/01/a-world-of-hellos/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Introduce yourself Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Troy.
Step 2. Say something about yourself Something about yourself
Step 3. Tell a joke Q: Where do astronauts like to get a drink?
A: At the space bar. #dadjokes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s connect!</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/connect/</guid>
      <description>troy.d.hamilton@comcast.net </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things I&#39;ve done</title>
      <link>https://troyhamilton.cloud/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://troyhamilton.cloud/resume/</guid>
      <description>AWS CERTIFIED SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT ASSOCIATE CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK PROFESSIONAL CCNP (SWITCH Only) CISCO CERTIFIED NETWORK ASSOCIATE CCNA MICROSOFT CERTIFIED SYSTEMS ENGINEER MCSE B.S. INFORMATION SECURITY  DIRECTOR OF INFRASTRUCTURE AND CLOUD SERVICES | JULY 2015 TO PRESENT  Responsible for entire IT infrastructure and key principal in data operations for nationwide client base In-depth monitoring, maintenance, and capacity planning for virtual machines, storage, networking, applications, databases, and security Provides leadership and support for the development team on legacy, current, and planned software development projects Engages strongly with project management team for on boarding of new clients and accompanying project requirements Developed, tested, and deployed new RESTful microservices and API methodologies for gaining greater visibility into client side integrations Key points of interest: ASP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>